Lou Caponi

JavaScript Developer

Greater New York Area (631) 833-5798 www.loucaponi.com Idcaponi@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Passionate and driven web application developer with a focus on the frontend. Solid experience with modern in Javascript technologies, including AngularJS, ReactJS, and Node.js. Strong skills working with teams locally and offshore. Enthusiastic about writing robust, testable, reusable code, and exploring the evolving JS landscape.

SKILLS

Javascript (ES6), ReactJS, Redux, Vue, AngularJS, HTML, CSS, Sass, Node.js, Express, Git, MongoDB, SQL

EXPERIENCE

CA Technologies, Islandia, NY - Senior Applications Developer

August 2017 - PRESENT

- Oversee and train a team of developers building multiple applications using React and Redux
- Rebuild a legacy PHP CRM-style application using React, Redux, Bootstrap 4, AG-Grid
- Built out a Contact/Account faceted search engine using React and Azure Search
- Built a web-based application for managing Sales and Marketing campaigns using React
- Heavily involved in CI/CD for all applications, using Visual Studio Team Services for version control, build and release definitions and deployments
- Heavy use of Git to manage features, releases, bug fixes, and pull requests from offshore teams
- Use modern frontend tooling including ES6, Webpack, Babel, Sass, Jest, Enzyme, Mocha/Chai
- Use Node.js for writing microservices in Azure
- Collaborate strongly with a small team, onshore and offshore, to accomplish deliverables under tight deadlines

Raymond James Financial via FDM Group, St. Petersburg, FL - Ul Developer

June 2015 - July 2017

- Developed flexible, reusable components for a dashboard/reporting application using Angular JS.
- Use Grunt/Gulp for building/bundling and Less for styling
- Managed development of multiple features simultaneously using the Gitflow workflow.
- Increased collaboration and code quality by performing normal code reviews.
- Met business deliveries by communicating with backend teams, business analysts, and QA team.

FDM Group, New York, NY- Consultant in Training - Java Development

March 2015 - June 2015

- Completed 4 month training program, focusing on developing full-stack enterprise Java applications.
- Gained development skills ranging from backend development (Java, SQL, JDBC, Hibernate), to frontend (JSP's, Javascript).
- Learned industry standard best practices, including TDD (JUnit), design patterns (Factory, Observer, Singleton), single responsibility, and code encapsulation.

EDUCATION

University of South Florida, Tampa, FL- M.A. in Pure and Applied Mathematics

August 2011 - May 2014

Southeastern University, Lakeland, FL- B.A. in Mathematics

August 2008 - May 2011

INTERESTS

Love to surf and snowboard, and get in the gym to destress. Like to explore local restaurants with friends. Try to get out of the country once or twice a year to keep things interesting.